[MUSIC]
Maine, when you last snarp anything, here.
Damn it, you're shaking.
All that chrome's messing with your nerves.
When this is all over, got a refit,
go lights back, reduce your load.
It's just some jitters, ain't nothing to worry about.
You can't keep this up, babe.
Fuck that, a little meadow ain't gonna be enough to hurt.
Maine?
Fuck off, ain't nobody gonna set my limits but me.
Maybe this goddamn far without trouble ain't about to back right now.
Where's our fucking data?
Kiwi's mid dive, can't rush her, you know that.
[MUSIC]
I guess it's harder to break through than I thought it'd be.
[SOUND]
Maine.
Stop, shit, what are you?
Hey!
Kiwi, Maine, Falco.
Jesus, you back with us?
D'Oio, what gives?
What the hell happened?